Um hello everyone. Um I'm Oxan uh CEO
and co-ounder of any shift. Um I'm sorry
in advance for my French accent. Um at
any shift we are building some AI SVS
based on a deep knowledge graph of the
infrastructure and today I'm going to
showcase example of why uh LLMs uh G
propilot cursor um break sometimes
infrastructure. So maybe first of all so
everyone has answered practically yes to
say that you're using AI for code
generation uh but who is used to
actually like create some infrastructure
as code uh in their
day-to-day not that many people h okay I
will try to to make it as simple as I
can I like to try to explain some
concepts uh if you have some question
yeah not too close because it's disturb
no it's like a compression thank you
thanks Okay. So maybe do like up and
downs. Thank you. When it's not
working. Um okay. So um let's see why
LLMs for infrastructure uh are not
perfect and the inevent limitation that
they have in their day today.
Um and today I want to speak and
highlight the importance of context when
it comes to uh code
generation and in this case for
infrastructure. Um what I did here uh
was actually um asking a simple task uh
to different type of AI and code
generation uh which is uh kind of a task
that a develops or an SV in your team uh
would do. Um here what I'm just asking
would be like in terapform which is an
infrastructure as code pipeline uh to
create a VPCP connection. So basically
connect a two VPC that would be normally
yours like of your company and of
another vendor for
instance. And so the first thing um that
I could get as an answer and here I'm
illustrating for a dev a developer so a
software engineer uh would be that
making a VPC pairing connection is
actually connecting two VPC togethers
together and in AWS or GCP uh you would
get the ids of those VPCs and
so ah sorry
uh better like that. Yes. Okay. Thank
you. Um and so like an easy thing to do
would be is it better? Perfect. Thanks.
Um would be to copy paste copy paste uh
the ideas to make the connection. Um bad
thing is that uh when you are like an or
devops in your team, it's actually a bad
practice to do so. Uh if you keep those
articled values, you make you may break
your pipeline. uh next time you're
actually applying in change in
production. So you should use dynamic
references. Um those dynamic references
are here. Um kind of a standard uh when
you're dev uh and uh that would be kind
of a good practice that GitHub copilot
would follow. I'm going to make those
dynamic references.
The thing is because um I'm not
referencing to the ID of my VPCs
anymore, uh I'm missing a reference to
my VPC. And so what copilot would do is
to actually try to make sense of this
reference and continue code generation
by defining a new VPC. Uh issue is it's
not the correct one. Uh this is just
hallucination.
uh because copilot doesn't have the
fences and the dependencies in
context. So I guess the big question
that everyone is thinking of is can
cursor do it because cursor have all
those dependencies are like wins etc uh
in
hand.
Um this is just for reference uh how the
white code should look like. Um I have
my dynamic references uh with my two
different VPCs and in another repository
uh I actually have a pointer uh to a
data source uh which is a reference to
my already existing VPC uh in my
cloud. Um but now let's go back uh to my
developer and to the IDs that he has in
hand. um those ids that reference uh to
your existing machines or like
configuration in your cloud is actually
only available in your cloud.
uh when you try to make a link between
those
values and like a reference of a name uh
in another repository something that
cursor would try to do it's actually
impossible completely impossible to make
the link because there is no direct
connection between this ID and this
reference and because of that uh tools
such as cursor winds surf etc because
they don't have access to your ids or
ends
H in your different like cloud providers
cannot generate the right infrastructure
as code. They can do something which is
80/20 but it will never be
perfect. Um I just want to illustrate
very quickly uh how this look like a
very basic example. Uh, I'm gonna use
cursor and I'm going to actually
zoom and I'm just going to list
my
inseure.
Um, cursor very
basic. Uh, I am user
sorry. Uh I just want to showcase here
that cursor is capable of reading uh
through all my uh
repositories. Uh and actually it's even
not responding well. So you can see that
when I'm asking cursor to list some IM
users, it's kind of failing to do so.
Expected answer would be like to list um
IM users in my different repositories.
Um what I wanted to illustrate would be
that actually when I'm looking at this
specific uh repo I have a list of all my
M users
uh Stephan
Jordan um Wen Fisher but when I go on
AWS which is here uh if I have a list of
all my IM users uh some of them are not
defined in cursor because they were
manually defined in your console.
Some things are sometimes not properly
defined uh in your code and only living
in your cloud. And because of that I
have here for instance a temporary user
that I have clickups. I've just created
it on the console and so cursor would be
strictly
impossible strictly incapable sorry uh
to generate it with uh its right uh
policy uh which is attached to it
because it's missing the context.
And so if I go back uh to the importance
of context when it comes to code
generation applied to infrastructure. Um
the last part of this talk is about the
fact that your infrastructure is a graph
and it should be understood and taken as
is
um it's a graph and it's complex. Uh
this kind of a representation a snapshot
of how it is built. um with all the
different nodes that interact a node
being like um um compute instance um and
linked so this would be for instance
like an EC2 instance linked to an IM
linked to another like two instance so
everything that you have like in your
different cloud providers uh it's way
more complex than that you can have like
multiple accounts multiple clouds 10 or
thousand of resources so actually uh
your infrastructure uh looks more like
that's uh than something else.
Um I just want to finish this talk uh by
speaking about how to solve those
issues. Um two main uh path uh of
actually solution and how to build that.
Um the first one is to build a graph DB.
This is what we do at any shift. uh we
build this knowledge graph of the
infrastructure where we are actually
going to map all the different cloud
resources Kubernetes one u nodes from
your codebase to make sense out of all
those relationship for code generation
um this takes a lot of time um you need
to process all those different live data
coming from different resources and so
it's time heavy and hard to maintain to
do internally
uh a second option uh which is already
great is to use MCB servers. Um I guess
who knows and use MCB server in this
room? Yeah, many of you. So for
instance, you have like the AWS one. Um
uh which is great. You have also like
the Kubernetes one which has just been
released. Um they can already give you
uh the life context about your
infrastructure but they miss uh the
dependencies between those cross
vendors. uh if you want to understand
that you have like an EKS cluster uh and
within cube uh that is in AWS you're
missing the fact that you have multiple
uh instances from multiple sources that
are
interacting and I think we won't have
time for this part but if you have any
question thank you so much and uh thanks
thanks for listening
[Applause]
questions.
Yeah.
Uh what is any shift? Um so we label
oursel as an SAB. Um so we have like um
a chatbot where you can ask any question
about your infrastructure. uh so in term
of cost compliance infrastructure
management uh why can't I connect to my
ads uh what is happening uh so those
kind of question um we do also like code
generation uh so imagine so our chatbot
you're asking a question about do I have
something which is not properly defined
my code um I just got an incident uh
what should I do and it will also like
create a pull request out of this
analysis this and then remediation. So
really like you can you can see oursel
as kind of an a dein of your
infrastructure.
Yeah. Do you have server that backs?
Yeah. uh so you can use RMCB server that
is actually um mapping our knowledge
graph that reconciles different sources
of data and so when you call it in
cursor you would get like super like
code
generation. Thank you.